Land and Freedom is a war, drama, history film directed by Ken Loach.
David Carr is a British Communist who is unemployed.
In 1936, when the Spanish Civil War begins, he decides to fight for the Republican side, a coalition of liberals, communists and anarchists, so he
joins the POUM militia and witnesses firsthand the betrayal of the Spanish revolution by Stalin's followers and Moscow's orders.
David Carr, played by Ian Hart.
Blanca, played by Rosana Pastor.
Bernard, played by Frédéric Pierrot.
Maite, played by Icíar Bollaín.
Lawrence, played by Tom Gilroy.
Kitty, played by Angela Clarke.
Land and Freedom (or Tierra y Libertad) is a 1995 film
directed by Ken Loach and written by Jim Allen.
The film narrates the story of David Carr, an unemployed worker and member of the Communist Party of Great Britain,
who decides to fight in the Spanish Civil War for the republicans against a nationalist coup d'état.
The film won the FIPRESCI International Critics Prize and the Prize of
the Ecumenical Jury at the 1995 Cannes Film Festival.
The film was also nominated for the Palme d'Or at Cannes.
The film explores themes of worker, spain, solidarity, revolution, fascism.
The tone is emotional.